Michael O'Rourke

Product Manager for Cloud, Web, and Digital Marketplaces

TOWN Dallas, Texas PHONE 512-740-4491

EMAIL <u>cale.orourke@gmail.com</u> **LINKEDIN** <u>linkedin.com/in/caleorourke</u>

Forward-thinking product manager with 15 years experience managing the strategy and execution for cloud, web, and digital products. Solid reputation for hatching profitable strategies, aligning business and development pillars, and taking new products from concept, to development, to delivery.

Tech-savvy and analytical with a background in product and program management, front-end design, and software development. Adept at building diverse, high-tech products in fast-paced environments. Additional qualifications include:

- Degree in Management Information Systems
- Certified Product Owner, PMP, ScrumMaster, and more
- Working knowledge of Agile, Lean, DevOps, and Offering Management
- Continuing education in Information Technology
- Proficiency in CSS/LESS, HTML, Jekyll, jQuery, Node, and SQL

Experience

Product Portfolio Manager

IBM CLOUD, 2012 – Present Dallas, Texas

Pivot product initiatives and market strategies toward developing a growing cloud computing platform. Responsible for building and launching new cloud PaaS and laaS products in global marketplaces.

- Establish new vertical products in Bluemix, SoftLayer, and IBM marketplace catalogs
- Craft business cases, proofs-of-concept, and requirements for dev consumption
- Enact strategies to reach untapped markets and new growth opportunities
- Capture market demands and architect plans to ensure "whole product" success
- Align technology roadmaps and P&L to drive organic growth and achieve business objectives
- Work directly with developers, designers, and customers to transform user/buyer needs into empathic feature-sets

Senior Product Manager

NEOPOST ID, 2003 - 2012

Austin, Texas

Cultivated pipelines to new markets and designed offerings for new online solutions and native apps. Responsible for customer-facing SaaS, on-premise, and digital products.

- Reached new markets by transitioning native products to hosted ecosystems
- Facilitated technology refresh programs to eliminate churn and increase revenue flow
- Adopted new Agile and Product Portfolio practices, reducing time-to-market by 40%
- Managed \$25M project to transform line-of-business apps into a hosted CRM environment
- Launched storefront for purchasing Internet-enabled apps on smart devices, increasing attachment rates 30-32% each guarter

Technical Project Consultant

SPRINT NEXTEL, 2000 – 2002 Plano. Texas

Spearheaded retail launches for mobile products and provided operational support for system hardware, networks, and back-office systems.

- Ushered in technology induction programs for ION broadband, 3G, and new mobile devices
- Coordinated new firmware builds, onsite implementations, and system updates during planned/unplanned maintenance windows
- Gathered quantitative data to report failures and serviceability issues

Education

B.S., Information Technology

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY, #22889837

Advanced studies in digital imaging, graphic design, security, web and software integration, networking, and enterprise technology.

A.A., Management Information Systems

LIBERTY UNIVERSITY, #22889837

Core foundations of technology, application software, current programming languages, and managing developmental cycles in business environments.

Certifications

Project Management Professional (PMP)

PROJECT MANAGEMENT INSTITUTE, #1386298

Practical Product Management Certified

PRAGMATIC MARKETING

Certified Scrum Product Owner

SCRUM ALLIANCE, #106785

Certified Scrum Professional

SCRUM ALLIANCE, #106785

Certified ScrumMaster

SCRUM ALLIANCE, #106785

Network+ Certified

COMPTIA, #COMP1006245476